well that was our tool chain from last week
这是我们上周的工具链
this week is different javascript
这周是不一样的的 javascript
let me just put this
让我把它放一下
i have a three production already
我已经有三个产品已经
just named after me, four
以我的名字命名了, 是四个
my job is to keep our code running
我的工作是保持我们的代码运行
while other packages are changing theirs
而其他软件包正在改变他们的代码。
should you learn javascript nope
你应该学习javascript吗 算了吧
is there any other option ? no
有没有其他选择？ 没有
oh look another library was added today to patch
看， 今天又增加了一个库
the problems of the other 150 that were also released
以修补其他150个已发布库的问题
did you know javascript
你知道javascript
was actually written in seven days
实际上是在 7 天内编写的
such a messy language i love it
这样一种混乱的语言，我喜欢它
did you know javascript was actually not written in seven days
你知道javascript实际上不是用七天写成的吗
no one ever knows what value
没有人知道，变量是什么值
variable is or what its type is,  now we use typescript
或者它的类型是什么, 现在我们在用typescript
we still don't know
我们还是不知道
i'd rather use rust or webassembly
我宁愿使用rust或webassembly
they say adoption is coming
他们说 adoption(没听懂) 就要来了
they said that 10 years ago
他们10年前就这么说了
they say that every year but this year is different
他们每年都这么说 但今年不同
is it scalable no
是否具有可扩展性 没有
is it maintainable no is it portable
是否可以维护 不行 是否具有可移植性
not really yeah we use react we actually
并非如此 我们用 React, 我们实际上
use Preact we actually use svelte
用 Preact ,我们实际上使用 svelte
we actually went back to vanilla javascript
我们最终回到了原生 javascript
yeah we're using a library for this that
是的，我们为此使用了一个库
we rewrote to vanilla javascript
我们将其重写为原生 javascript
because it wasn't efficient we're stuck with
因为它效率不高，我们被
this messy language
这种混乱的语言困住了
now i love it javascript yeah
现在我爱它 javascript
it's the defacto standard do you know there's a
这是事实上的标准，你知道有一个
library for that i wouldn't trust the
库可以做那个吗 我应该不相信的
let's say finance application with
假设财务应用程序使用
javascript what our finance application
javascript 我们的财务应用程序
does is totally fine to use javascript
所做的事情完全可以使用 javascript
but i'd recommend using typescript not that we do
但我建议使用 typescript 而不是我们所做的那样
we had callback hell
我们有回调地狱
and then we went to promises
然后我们转向了promises
await came out went back to promises and now we
await来了 然后我们回到了promises 现在我们
rewrote everything back to callbacks
又重写了所有的东西回到了回调
because it's just more comfortable
只是因为它写起来更舒服
at least you know it's bad
至少你知道它不怎么样
oh it's probably just a quick fix
它可能只是一个quick fix
will take me three to five days to find it
我们花了三到五天才找到它
we tried coffeescript rewrote our codebase
我们尝试了coffeescript 重写了我们的代码库
try typescript rewrote our codebase and then
我们尝试了typescript 重写了我们的代码库
we went back to vanilla javascript
然后我们回到了原生 javascript
because it's just more comfortable so we
因为它只是更舒服，所以我们
rewrote our codebase again yeah
重写了我们的代码库
we used react and then react 16.8 came out and
我们先是在用 react 然后 react 16.8 出来了，
we had to rewrite everything to hooks
我们必须得用 hooks 重写
react 17 came out we had to rewrite everything again
react 17 出来了，我们不得不再次重写
and then react script
然后 react script
was updated to version 0.4
脚本更新到版本 0.4
and we had to fix everything
我们必须修复一大堆东西
to work with local images and
来使用本地图片
now react version 18 is coming out
现在 react 18 出来了
we'll rewrite everything again
我们不得不再次重写
we rewrote our code base around nine times this month yeah
在这个月我们重写了9次我们的代码库
you can use redux totally fine but but
你可以使用 redux 完全没问题，但
if you're on it i'd recommend you use
如果你在使用它，我建议你使用
redux toolkit but actually it's better
redux toolkit 但实际上
to use flux or Flummox or flexible?(没听懂)
最好使用flux或Flummox 或 mobx,zustand,jotai,valtio (up加的)
actually better to use Recoil not that
实际上更好地使用 Recoil 而不是
we do but now react came out with the
我们这样做，但现在 react 自带有
hooks and context api which apparently
hooks 和 context api 这显然
is better than redux apparently we'll
比 redux 更好，显然我们会
rewrite everything again
再次重写全部
sometimes it just doesn't transpire
有时候它不会触发
we usually rewrite our code base
我们通常重写我们的代码库
now we actually wrote a custom transpiler to transpile transpiler
现在我们实际上编写了一个自定义的转译器来转译转译器
it's such a messy language
它是如此混乱的语言
we use it for our website desktop app
我们将它用于我们的网站、桌面应用、
mobile app for the fridge the tesla
手机软件、冰箱、特斯拉
it's not actually native
实际上并不是原生
i mean it is actually native but it's sort of not
我的意思是他实际上是原生的但它不是
really native it's sort of hybrid native
真正的原生它是一种混合原生
but some of it is native i mean some
但是有一部分是原生的，我的意思是有些
people use it in a native way
人以原生方式使用它
but we don't really use it in a native way
但我们并没有真正以原生方式使用它
technically a lot of people are
从技术上讲，很多人正在
switching back to native
切换回原生
no one has switched yet
但现在还没有人转换回去
Angular? talk to me when you use Angular 2 or react
Angular? 当你使用 Angular 2 或 react 的时候，再跟我说吧
npm is such a bad package manager
npm 是一个糟糕的包管理器，
no one uses that anymore npm is such a
没有人再用它了 npm 是一个
good package manager how many languages have one
很好的包管理器，有多少种语言有一个，
so that major version breaks
所以主要版本破坏
our code but our code breaks the minor
了我们的代码，但我们的代码破坏了次要
version i still don't know how to fix
版本，直到今天我仍然不知道如何修复
peer dependencies until this day
peer dependencies
yarn pnpm turbo would make sense right
yarn pnpm turbo 才有意义，对
javascript doesn't think so
javascript 不这么认为
jquery? what are you five
jquery? 你5岁吗
we use jj query global variables
我们用 jjquery(没听懂) 全局变量
no one uses them it must be somewhere in the window
没有人使用它它必然在window对象的某个地方
how do you debug node apps
你是怎么调试node应用的
you don't you just write good code
你不行的，你只能把代码写好
in javascript no one ever masters javascript
在 javascript 中没有人精通javascript
i get a hundred thousand
在stack overflow 上
points in stack overflow
我获得了 10 万分
i'm still a noob node is technically multi-threaded
我仍然是一个菜鸟， node 在技术上是多线程的
javascript is technically performant
javascript 在技术上是高性能的
our code
我们的代码
is never safe when they'll blow up
在炸了的时候永远不安全
probably won't work anymore
可能不再起作用
probably will be using rust or webassembly or whatever js
可能会使用 rust 或 webassembly 或
an array is technically
数组在技术上是
just an object, object is object
只是一个对象, 对象是对象
null is technically not an object
null 在技术上不是一个对象
but objects can be null so they technically can be
但对象可以是null 因此它们在技术上也可以是
non-object unless they're an object
非对象，除非它们是对象
right so technically null is an object
对的，所以从技术上讲 null 是一个对象，
yes
是的
it's a bit hacky i admit
我承认它有点魔法
but javascript is by design
但是 javascript 是设计使然
is it easy to learn
它很容易学习?
have you tried javascript
你有尝试过 javascript 吗
probably will be a bit hacky
可能会有点 hacky
have you used javascript before? i don't recommend
你之前用过 javascript 吗？ 我不推荐
i don't like our tool chain documentation
我不喜欢我们的工具链文档
and another advantage is that it's free
另一个优点是它是免费的
so was java before it was bought byoracle
Java 在被 oracle 购买之前也是免费的，
so we prepare ourselves by installing
所以我们从npm安装模块
modules from npm then we compile it to
为自己做准备 ，然后我们将其编译为
typescript then we use a term compiler
typescript，然后我们使用一个名为 babel 的编译器
called babel to transpile it to es5
将其转换为 es5
load it with system.js file for
然后用 system.js 加载它的编译结果
bankruptcy bundle it all up with webpack
用 webpack 把它全部打包
use it in a framework like react
在诸如 react 之类的框架中使用它
and let the state be managed by redux or flux
并让状态由 redux 或
Flummox or flexible or recoil or
Flummox 或 flexible 或者 recoil 或
whatever js and voila(没听懂)
其他的什么 js 管理  mobx,zustand,jotai,valtio (up加的)
all of this just to avoid using jquery
瞧 所有这些只是为了避免使用 jquery
or in our case jjquery but that'll be
或在我们的例子中是 jjquery(没听懂) 但这
probably less performant
可能会降低性能，
as most of the things this isn't our
因为大多数事情这不是我们的
production code it will be tomorrow
产品代码，明天
though probably gonna get fired again
可能会再次被抛弃，
i mean there's really no alternative to
我的意思是对于javascript
javascript right now
到现在真的别无选择
defacto no one really knows what the value is until we
实际上，直到我们碰到error之前
get an error
没人真正知道某个值具体是什么
i love it we're try writing anything
我爱它 我们现在尝试在
without javascript nowadays
没有 javascript 的情况下编写一些东西
javascript i love it
javascript 我爱它
no i don't recommend it
不，我不推荐它